Mansfield Park is a drama, tv movie film directed by Iain B. MacDonald.
Fanny Price is sent to live with her wealthy relatives, the Bertrams,
where she is treated poorly by most except her cousin Edmund.
Her life is complicated by the arrival of the worldly Mary and Henry Crawford
Fanny Price, played by Billie Piper.
Edmund Bertram, played by Blake Ritson.
Mary Crawford, played by Hayley Atwell.
Maria Bertram, played by Michelle Ryan.
Henry Crawford, played by Joseph Beattie.
Rushworth, played by Rory Kinnear.
Mansfield Park is a 2007 British television film directed by Iain B.
MacDonald and starring Billie Piper, Michelle Ryan, and Blake Ritson.
Adapted from Jane Austen's classic 1814 novel of the same name, the film is about Fanny Price, who
is sent by her poor mother to live with wealthy relatives at their Mansfield estate.
By the age of eighteen, Fanny is in love with her sensitive
cousin who is studying to be a clergyman.
Her feelings for him and her moral sense prevent her from accepting
a marriage proposal from a much wealthier suitor.
Mansfield Park premiered on 18 March 2007 on the United Kingdom network
ITV at 9:00 p.m., as part of The Jane Austen Season.
It was filmed at Newby Hall, North Yorkshire, England.
It made its TV debut in Canada on 23 December 2007 and
in the United States on 27 January 2008.
The drama ran for two hours (including advertisement breaks) in
the United Kingdom, 90 minutes without the breaks.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, period drama, 19th century.
The tone is emotional.